HUGO KAWAMATA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

0478051841

hugokawamata@gmail.com

hugokawamata.com

SKILLS

Software Architecture and Programming

Delivery Management

Tabletop Game Design

Self-Taught Japanese

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Comp Sci)

University of Queensland

2015-2018

GPA 6.81

LANGUAGES

English

Japanese





PROFILE

Although I work in tech, when I'm not at the office I usually spend my time on nontech related projects. I spend a lot of time writing about linguistics and language acquisition, which I post on my blog. My linguistic/language knowledge is due in part to my experience learning Japanese, which I am conversationally fluent in. I also do digital art and drawing with Posca paint pens. Besides that, I have knowledge and experience in designing tabletop games, and I have actually published a small card game, called Hierarchy. You can find the link to purchase on my website.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead

2022-2023 Tanda

- Full stack development in Ruby on Rails and React.
- Closely working with product managers to determine what customer problems to develop solutions for.
- Requirements gathering talking to customer facing shareholders and product managers to determine exactly what is required for customers to deem the work we do a "success".
- Planning a whole team's work on projects so that up to 5 developers can work on the same part of the codebase concurrently.
- Directing and reviewing code to ensure on-time delivery of requirements.
- Effective scope cutting when delivery of all requirements unexpectedly becomes
- Giving candid and constructive feedback which results in positive change in the organisation.

Developer / Senior Developer

2018-2021 Tanda

- Full stack development in Ruby on Rails, React, and React Native.
- Worked primarily on the Tanda mobile app for the first year (React Native).
- Following that, worked primarily on the web app (Ruby on Rails and React).

